[
    {
        "question": "A meeting of all major political parties in India was organized at ……………  to consider the Wavell plan",
        "options": [
            "Delhi",
            "Srinagar",
            "Simla",
            "Chennai"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "As per …………… India got Independence.",
        "options": [
            "Mountbatten Plan",
            "Wavell plan",
            "Indian Independence Act",
            "Cabinet Mission"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Gandhiji was assassinated on …………… .",
        "options": [
            "30 Dec 1947",
            "30 Jan 1948",
            "30 Mar 1948",
            "2 Oct 1948"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "…………… opposed the plan of partition.",
        "options": [
            "Muslim League",
            "INC"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Viceroy …………… established the Interim Government.",
        "options": [
            "Mount batter",
            "Pethick Lawrence",
            "A. V. Alexander",
            "Wavell"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "The followers of …………… resorted to violent ways.",
        "options": [
            "I N C",
            "Congress",
            "Muslim league",
            "Pakistan"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The Muslim League decided to observe 16 August as …………… day.",
        "options": [
            "Non violence",
            "Pakistan",
            "Direct Action",
            "Independence"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Indian attained Independence from the …………… years of slavery",
        "options": [
            "150",
            "200",
            "175",
            "125"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "In ……………  a delegation of British ministers namely Pethick Lawrence, Stafford Cripps and A. V. Alexander put forth England’s plan regarding India.",
        "options": [
            "March 1945",
            "March 1946",
            "August 1945",
            "August 1946"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Gandhiji was brutally assassinated by …………… .",
        "options": [
            "Nathuram Godse",
            "Surandarnath",
            "Ramsay",
            "Ravindra Ghosh"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "On 15 August 1947, the two independent nations of India and …………… were to come into existence.",
        "options": [
            "Bangladesh",
            "Pakistan",
            "China",
            "Nepal"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "After the end of ……………  the British rulers were in favour of granting freedom to India.",
        "options": [
            "Second world war",
            "First world war"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "…………… prepared a plan of creation of India and Pakistan as two independent nations.",
        "options": [
            "Lord Wavell",
            "Atlee",
            "Lord Mountbatten",
            "Winston Churchill"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Barrister …………… put forth the two Nation theory and demanded a separate Muslim nation named Pakistan",
        "options": [
            "Mohammad Ali Jinnah",
            "Muhammad Iqbal",
            "Aga Khan",
            "Chaudhary Rahmat Ali"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The Indian National Congress was founded on the principle of …………… .",
        "options": [
            "Secularism",
            "Socialism",
            "Political",
            "Economies"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "…………… Prime minister of England had announced that England would leave its dominion on India before June 1948.",
        "options": [
            "Winston Churchil",
            "Atlee",
            "Lord Mountbatten",
            "Lord Wavell"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The Union Jack of Britain was lowered and in its place the Indian …………… flag was unfurled",
        "options": [
            "Tiranga",
            "Tricolour"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1930, …………… a well known poet put forth the thought of an independent Muslim state.",
        "options": [
            "Chaudhary Rahmat Ali",
            "Mohammad Ali Jinnah",
            "Aga Khan",
            "Dr. Muhammad Iqbal"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "The British …………… over the princely states will also come to an end.",
        "options": [
            "Power",
            "Supremacy",
            "Authority",
            "Need"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "There were …………… in the Noakhali region in the province of Bengal.",
        "options": [
            "Massacres",
            "Riots",
            "Fights",
            "Conflict"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The demand for …………… of India was gaining its strength.",
        "options": [
            "Freedom",
            "Independence"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    }
]